http://www.bentham.co.uk/cookies-privacy-policy/

HomeCookies & Privacy Policy
Welcome to the Bentham Instruments Privacy Notice This Privacy Notice is designed to help you understand everything you need to know about the what, why and how’s of our data gathering and processing operations, and what your legal rights are.We hope you’ll take some time to read this document; we’ve tried to keep it all as simple as possible and we will keep you informed if there are any changes to the way we process your personal data in the future, before making them.Bentham Instruments takes its responsibility of protecting your data very seriously and we do advise you get to know our practices – If there’s anything in this policy you don’t understand or if you want to ask any questions, please feel free to contact us using any of the details below.Who are we?We are Bentham Instruments, a UK Limited Company registered in England and Wales at 2 Boulton Road, Reading, Berkshire, RG2 0NH, United Kingdom (Company Registration No. 01197391). In this document Bentham Instruments will sometimes be referred to as “we”.What kind of personal data might we ask you to provide?Bentham Instruments will only ever ask for personal data if it is required for a specific purpose; with that in mind we have created a full list of all the kinds of personal data that we may ask you to provide in order to achieve those purposes. The kinds of personal data we may collect are:
Student
Same as employee
Job applicant
Contact details plus CV
Customer
Name, address, telephone, email, business name
Subscriber (mailing list)
Name, usually business email
Supplier
Name, address, telephone, email, B2B plus bank details
Why do we collect personal data?We will use personal data firstly to fulfil any contractual obligations that exist between us and yourself; where we request personal data be provided to meet the terms of any such contract you will be required to provide the relevant personal data or we will not be able to deliver the goods and/or services you want. In such cases the lawful basis of us processing the personal data is that it is necessary for the performance of a contract.We may also process your personal data in accordance with our legitimate business interests; this is on the considered measure that we need the personal data to achieve the various purposes and that it could be reasonable for an individual to expect their data to be used for those purposes.Our data processing activities conducted on the lawful basis of ‘legitimate interests’ are:To provide you with goods and services you are looking forTo inform you of other goods and services we provide, or offers that may interest you (direct marketing)To send notifications on subjects you have subscribed to, or otherwise asked us to keep you informed ofTo improve the quality of the services we offer, and to better understand our customers’ needs by requesting feedback, or requesting you review the services we have provided, or we may send survey forms that we ask you to completeTo notify you of any changes to the goods and/or services we provide, or have provided, that may affect youTo allow us to support and maintain our products in active serviceImprove website so content is delivered more efficientlyWe may also process your personal data in order for Bentham Instruments to comply with our various legal obligations; this might include:Providing for financial commitments between us and yourself, or to relevant financial authoritiesComplying with industry regulatory requirements and any self-regulatory schemesCarrying out required business operations and due diligence; e.g. administration, security, reorganisations, investment or corporate/asset salesCooperating with relevant authorities for reporting criminal activity, or to detect and prevent fraudWhere did we obtain your personal data?Other than collecting data directly from you, we may gather personal data from cookies that gather data over time when you visit our online platforms.Cookies may be used by the Website to allow us to recognise you and your preferred settings e.g. to store your ID and password for future sessions. This saves you from re-entering information on return visits to the Website. You have the option not to use this feature, in which event no cookies will be retained on your computer.If the site has a secure log-in for our registered users, it may use a temporary ’session cookie’ in order to perform the secure login to our website. This cookie contains no personal information, just a long random number, and is deleted from your web browser when you exit the Website.Temporary cookies are used in the transactional part of the Website to authenticate you as an authorised user after you have logged in.Your browser may be capable of being programmed to reject cookies, or to warn you before downloading cookies, and information regarding this may be found in your browser’s ‘help’ facility.For an explanation of cookies see the All About Cookies website.If you have any questions regarding the use of cookies please contact us.Below is a table of all cookies on this website – their name, type and purpose:
Cookie Type
Cookie Name
Cookie Purpose
Session & TYPO3 Content Management Cookie
session & fe_typo_user
We use session cookies to record an individual users preferences that the user has specified, so that each time the user returns their preferences remain. Commonly this would be language settings, shopping carts, anything where you have indicated a preference. Where forms are used on the site, we hold the information in a session cookie so that we can improve the user experience on the site. Should a user, for example, forget to fill in parts of a form when submitting a form, we can auto-fill the values for those fields that have been filled in, thereby reducing the amount of fields a user needs to amend. This information is stored only in your browser and is destroyed once your browser is closed.
Google Analytics
__utmz __utmc __utmb __utma
These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site for you. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.
Who will we share your information with?In order to achieve the above stated purposes for which we process your personal data, we may need to share your personal data with various third-party service providers who act as data processors.We may share your personal data with third party organisations acting as data controllers or with specific individuals, groups or other organisations who act as neither data controllers nor data processors, but only where we are either legally require to do so by law or where doing so is necessary to achieve the intended stated purpose of processing the data.In the event that we sell or reorganise our business, or if otherwise required by law or by an authorised regulator, we may transfer your personal data as a part of the general business data to the relevant parties.Where is my data going to be stored?Bentham Instruments will not transfer your personal data to any country outside the European Union (EU) other than those that have been granted an adequacy decision under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).We may be required to transfer your personal data to organisations who intend to transfer the data outside the EU. Where such transfers of data take place, we shall ensure that contracts are in place between the parties involved that ensure the recipient organisation has a suitable standard of data protection in place How long will we keep your data for?We will keep your personal data only for as long as required in order to achieve the purposes for which it was gathered, in line with this privacy notice.For determining when personal data should be erased we shall take into consideration the amount of and sensitivity of the personal data we have, the amount of harm that could be caused by a data breach, the benefits of the purposes the data is being used for and any legal requirements that we are bound to.You may request that we erase your personal data an anytime, though in cases where there is a remaining relevant or legal reason why we are required to keep the data we may opt to restrict the amount of processing being conducted to what is absolute necessary in line with your legal rights in order to minimise the impact the processing will have.Where the lawful basis of our processing is based on protection of vital interests and insofar any relevant health and safety obligations apply, Bentham Instruments will retain your personal data for 40 years.Your Rights, Our ResponsibilityThere are several rights granted to you immediately upon providing us with your personal information; some of these are mentioned above. We’d like you to know that at Bentham Instruments we take your rights as a Natural Person seriously and will always conduct ourselves in a way that is considerate of our responsibility to serve your legal rights.You have the Right of AccessThis grants you the right to confirm whether or not your personal data is being processed, and to be provided with relevant details of what those processing operations are and what personal data of yours is being processed. If you would like access to the personal data we have about you, we ask that you contact us by using any of the details below.The Right to RectificationThis one is fairly straight forward; if you notice that the data we have about you is inaccurate or incomplete, you may request we rectify the mistake. We will make every effort to respond to requests of this type immediately.The Right to ObjectionThe right to object is a basic freedom all democracies enjoy. If you wish to object to the way we use, or have used, your personal data you may do so freely.The Right to PortabilityThis is a legal right afforded to you that states we must pass on all of the details you have provided to us in a machine-readable format, either to your or to another provider of your choosing. The Right to ComplainWe will always try to maintain the highest standards and encourage the confidence our customers have in us as an organisation. In order that we can achieve this we do request that any complaints be first brought to our attention so we can properly investigate matters; if however you would like to complain about Bentham Instruments to a supervisory authority you may do so by contacting the Information Commissioners Office on 0303 123 1113, or anyone of the other reporting methods listed on their website - https://ico.org.uk/concernsOur contact detailsIf you wish to get in touch with Bentham Instruments regarding data gathering and processing operations please do so with any of the following contact details:Bentham Instruments Ltd2 Boulton RoadReadingBerkshireRG2 0NHT: +44 (0)118 975 1355@: DPO@bentham.co.uk
About usCareersTerms & ConditionsCookies & Privacy PolicyAccessibility StatementSitemapRepresentative Area
You are currently offline. Some pages or content may fail to load.
